The hopes of a nation rode on a long shot.
Seabiscuit is a drama, history film directed by Gary Ross.
True story of the undersized Depression-era racehorse whose victories lifted not
only the spirits of the team behind it but also those of their nation.
Red Pollard, played by Tobey Maguire.
Narrator, played by David McCullough.
Charles Howard, played by Jeff Bridges.
Tom Smith, played by Chris Cooper.
Marcela Howard, played by Elizabeth Banks.
George Woolf, played by Gary L. Stevens.
Seabiscuit is a 2003 American historical sports drama film co-produced, written and directed by Gary Ross and
based on the best-selling 1999 non-fiction book Seabiscuit: An American Legend by Laura Hillenbrand.
The film stars Tobey Maguire, Jeff Bridges, Chris Cooper,
Elizabeth Banks, Gary Stevens, William H.
Macy and Valerie Mahaffey and is loosely based on the life and racing career of Seabiscuit, an undersized and overlooked Thoroughbred race
horse, whose unexpected successes made him a hugely popular media sensation in the United States during the Great Depression.
Seabiscuit was released by Universal Pictures on July 25, 2003.
The film received positive reviews from critics and grossed
$148.3 million against an $87 million budget.
At the 76th Academy Awards, Seabiscuit received seven nominations, including Best Picture, but
ultimately lost all seven, including six to The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, horse
race, american dream, horse, racehorse.
The tone is emotional.